egames.net 2010-12-31

# Games - Download Free Online Games! | eGames: Support > PRIVACY STATEMENT

eGames has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our commitment to the privacy rights of our online users and to the purchasers of our products. At eGames, we strive to help our users protect their privacy while using our products and services. This privacy statement contains information about our website, our products, and the games and web applications offered by eGames and accessed through this website and third party websites (collectively, the “Services”). This privacy statement provides information about: what personally identifiable information of yours is collected; what organization is collecting the information; how the information is used; with whom the information may be shared; what choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information; and how you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. Please note that this policy relates only to eGames.com and eGames games or applications created by eGames and available through third party websites. This policy does not apply to websites or products developed and/or maintained by other companies to which we link or which provide services to our website. By using the Services, you agree to the collection and use of your personal information as outlined in this Privacy Policy, as this Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. You should visit this page periodically to review any changes to the Privacy Policy.

**Information Collected**

Examples of the information we collect and analyze while you use our Services, make a purchase, or register on our site include:

1\. the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet;  
2\. login;  
3\. e-mail address;  
4\. password;  
5\. computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system, and platform;  
6\. purchase history, which we sometimes aggregate with similar information from other customers to create features such as top sellers;  
7\. the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to, through, and from our website, including date and time;  
8\. cookie number; and  
9\. products you viewed or searched for.  
10\. When you install any of the eGames games or applications, we may collect and record the information you provide us voluntarily through the social networking website you use to access the Services in accordance with the terms and conditions of the social network website.

During some visits we may use software tools such as JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.

If you are purchasing a product on our website, the type of personal information collected includes: your name, zip code, email address, phone number, age and credit card information.

If you register to become a member of our website, the information that we collect includes your name, email address, and the country where you reside. Once you register as a user on our website, we will keep your purchase history, favorite games information, reviews you provide and your navigational history. When you become a registered user, you can choose to receive email notices about upcoming products and promotions from eGames by checking the box on the registration form. Information you submit when completing our online registration form will not be used for this purpose unless you indicate that you wish to receive such additional information when you fill out the registration form. We use the information from the registration form to better design our website, create better products, bring to market products that consumers are looking for, and, to the extent you have agreed, to send email messages notifying you of product news, special offers and promotions.

**What Organizations Collect Information**

When you purchase a product online or become a registered user of our website, you are providing the information identified above to eGames. We have also contracted with some third party entities to provide certain webhosting and transactional services for our website. They include: 1) The Planet, a host service which provides a software download hosting service, server space and bandwidth availability; and 2) Authorize.net, a credit card processing service. The host service maintains a secure database of customer information, including name, email address and zip code, but excluding any credit card information. The credit card processor utilizes a customer's credit card information to process debits or credits to the customer's credit card account as necessary. The entities whose servers handle these transactions maintain security measures designed to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of your user data under their control. They use physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect any personally identifiable data stored on their computers. Only authorized employees have access to the information you provide us. For more information about the privacy practices of our credit card processing service, Authorize.net, please visit www.authorize.net/company/privacy/. 

**The Way Your Information Is Used**

The information you provide about yourself when purchasing a product is used by eGames and the third-party credit card processing service to complete that order. Customers who buy products from the eGames website are shopping on a secure server, which encrypts all of the customers personal information including name, email address and credit card number. Encryption is used to block access and use of this information in an unauthorized manner. The eGames shopping cart uses Secure Socket Layers. This means that the data being sent to the eGames server from your browser is encrypted using high-level encryption technology.

The information you provide about yourself when becoming a registered user is used to analyze website traffic, to aggregate and analyze demographic information about visitors to our website, and for other business purposes, such as product development and marketing, advertising on our website, and business transactions with third parties.

**Who Your Information is Shared With**

When you become a registered user of our website, the information you provide -- email address, username, zip code, gender and birth date -- allows eGames to send you information that may be of interest to users of our site, including special offers, news and updates that relate directly to your specific interests. As part of the registration process, we give you the opportunity to decline to receive any of these communications from us.  
The data collected is used in the aggregate to give eGames demographic information about the entire audience registering to use the eGames wesbite. eGames uses this information to better understand that audience and to improve our offerings to our customers. We may also disclose this aggregated information to unaffiliated third parties (companies that are not owned or controlled by us) for various business purposes, including advertising, marketing and joint business efforts for related and unrelated products and services.

The information you provide when you purchase a product online is used to complete the transaction. Your personally identifiable information provided during the purchasing process is not shared with third parties, although aggregated demographic and purchasing information may be shared with third parties for advertising, marketing and other business purposes.

**What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information**

Users may opt out of receiving future notifications about new products and features by not checking the box at the bottom of the registration form. This option allows users to become a registered user without receiving promotional information. If you do not want the information that you provide on the user registration form to be shared with third parties, do not become a registered user of our website.

**How You Can Access or Correct Your Information**

You can access and change the information that we collect from you online during the registration process by going to the registration page, signing in with your password, and revising the information in the registration form.

**Cookies**

Cookies are pieces of information in the form of a small text file that a Website transfers to an individual's hard drive. The cookie transmits information back to the server that placed it, and most times can only be read by that server. Cookies can make Web-surfing easier for website visitors by saving the users preferences while at our site.

The use of cookies is an industry standard -- you'll find them at most major Web sites. By showing how and when visitors use a site, cookies help us see which areas of our website are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the site are based on the data collected by cookies such as the total number of visitors and pages viewed. This information is most easily tracked with cookies. We use the information from cookies to provide services better tailored to our users needs.

We have two primary uses for cookies. First, we use them to specify unique preferences. Secondly, we use cookies to track website user trends and patterns. This helps us to better understand and improve areas of our website. You may also get cookies from third-party advertisers. eGames does not control these cookies. The use of advertising cookies sent by third-party servers is standard in the Internet industry.

Most Internet browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent. If you take affirmative steps to decline cookies, it will not impair your ability to browse our website, but you will not be able to become a registered user, download trials of products or purchase products online unless cookies are accepted.

**Use of IP Addresses**

An IP address is a number that's automatically assigned to your computer whenever you're surfing the Web. Web servers -- the computers that "serve up" Web pages to your computer- automatically identify your computer by its IP address. eGames collects IP addresses for the purpose of tracking visitors usage of our site. We do not link IP addresses to any personally identifiable information, which means that a user's session will be logged, but the user remains anonymous to us. Personally identifiable information includes name, address, phone number and email address.

**Third Party Advertising**

eGames may use third-party online advertising on its Services to display advertisements. These third-party advertising services would be responsible for maintaining and displaying the advertisements you may see on our Services. Fox Networks serves ads on our Services and collects information about user interaction with those ads - information that cannot identify a particular person.

These services typically use cookies to collect data from browsers to aggregate statistical information. This includes IP addresses, browser types, operating systems, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding viewing of advertisements. These services do not, and cannot, collect personally identifiable information about visitors to our website, such as email address, name, phone number and street address.

**Childrens Guidelines**

eGames encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the activities offered by our Services. No information should be submitted to or posted at eGames.com by customers under 13 years of age without the consent of their parent or guardian. All customers under the age of 13 are required to have a parent register online for them. We currently do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13.

**Links to Other Sites**

Users should be aware that when they are at eGames.com, they could be directed to other sites that are beyond our control. There are links to other sites from eGames web pages and Services that take you outside our Services. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" takes you off the eGames site. This includes links to advertisers, website traffic auditing services, e-commerce service providers and co-branding partners. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information. The eGames privacy policy does not extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet, and therefore beyond the control of eGames.

**Your Consent**

By using our Services, you consent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Services.

**Changes to this Policy**

Here at eGames, we continuously work to expand and improve the eGames Services. When new features are added, we will incorporate the information collection and use practices stated in the policy. As our Services evolve, we may revise this policy, so please check back frequently.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this web site, please contact us at webmaster@egames.com.
